**Scheduled Maintenance on November 23**

Due to scheduled maintenance, our platforms, including the Contact Center, website, and Mi LUMA app, will be temporarily unavailable on **November 23 from 12:00 a.m. to 4:00 a.m.**

We apologize for any inconvenience and appreciate your understanding as we work to improve our systems.

**In case of an electrical emergency, please contact 911.**

* System Information

==============================================================

=========================================================================

==================================================

============================================================

===================================================================

====================================================

Privacy Policy
==============

LUMA ENERGY, LLC – PRIVACY POLICY
---------------------------------

LUMA Energy, LLC (“LUMA”) is committed to protecting your privacy and to protecting all personal and non-personal information we may collect from you while doing business and providing our services. We explain below what information we collect, what we do with this information, who we share it with, and under what circumstances. Please review this policy before using our website, mobile applications, social networks, messaging services, emails and chat services (collectively, our “Online Services”). Your use of the Online Services implies your consent to this policy. If you do not agree with this policy as a whole, or any part of it, please discontinue your use of our Online Services.

### Who we are

LUMA operates Puerto Rico’s electricity transmission and distribution system. LUMA’s affiliates include, but are not limited to, LUMA Energy ServCo, LLC and the Puerto Rico Electric Power Authority.

### How can you access our Online Services?

You can access our Online Services through our website and our mobile application (“App”).

Our website is available at [www.lumapr.com](https://www.lumapr.com/) and is divided into a public section and a private section. The public section of the website provides relevant general information that people may access without creating sign in credentials and without providing us any personal information. We do not collect any personal information from your interaction with the public website section. We may collect non-personal information from your device using cookies and/or other tracking mechanisms, but this information cannot be used to identify you.

The private section of the website provides personal electric service account information such as your account number, energy consumption, bills, and payments, among others, and provides several tools to manage your electric service accounts. To access the private website section, you must first register to create sign in credentials, including a username and a password. For that purpose, we will request your electric service account number among other personal information in order to identify you and authenticate you as the rightful owner of the electric service accounts that the private website section will present you.

For your convenience, we also provide an App to manage your electric service accounts. You can access the App by downloading it from the App Store in Apple devices or from the Google Play Store in Android or Google-based devices. The App provides its service by connecting to the private website section. Thus, if you created sign in credentials for the private website section, you can use the same sign in credentials to access the App. Otherwise, the process to gain access to the App is identical to the process to access the private website section; that is, the App will request some personal information to authenticate you and then you will create sign in credentials for access. The App may also use some of the authentication features of your device, such as touch-ID and face-ID.

In addition, we offer social media channels in Facebook, Twitter, Instagram, and LinkedIn. Through these channels we also provide relevant general information that people may access without providing us any personal information. These channels allow user generated content in the form of comments, images and videos which must adhere to our Terms and Conditions. We will never request any personal information through any of these channels as they are not secure channels of communication.

The table that follows describes each piece of personal information we request in order to provide you our Online Services, tells you why we need it, how we collect it, and if we store it and how.

### What personal information do we collect and how do we use it?

We may request personal information from you when you create sign in credentials in order to use the Online Services or when you contact us to request information or to request a service from us. The personal information we request is mainly used to identify you and to identify the electric service accounts you own or are authorized to manage. We only collect and store the personal information that you voluntarily share with us that is necessary for the purposes stated below.

| Type of information | Purpose | Collection | Storage |
| --- | --- | --- | --- |
| Name and last name | To identify you as a customer and to identify your electric service accounts, that is the electric service  <br>accounts that you are authorized to manage. | This information resides on our billing system from when you started your electric service. We request it from  <br>you when you create sign in credentials in order to authenticate you. | This information is maintained in the billing system and it is stored by the Online Services. |
| Username | To allow you to securely sign in to the private website section and to the App and to prevent others from  <br>accessing your accounts. | You establish it when you create sign in credentials. | This information is stored in the private website section for use during user sign in for the website and App. |
| Password | To allow you to securely sign in to the private website section and to the App and to prevent others from  <br>accessing your accounts. | You establish it when you create sign in credentials. | This information is stored in the private website section for use during user sign in for the website and App.  <br>It is protected with additional security tools. |
| E-mail | To send you email notifications related to your service, to offer you additional services, to deliver marketing  <br>or promotional messages, or to request your feedback, among others. | You provide it when you have contact with us or when you create sign in credentials. | This information is stored by the Online Services and by our billing system. You may update this information. |
| Telephone number | To send you text message notifications related to your service, to offer you additional services or to deliver  <br>marketing or promotional messages, or to request your feedback, among others. | You provide it when you have contact with us or when you create sign in credentials. | This information is stored by the Online Services and by our billing system. You may update this information. |
| Postal address | To send you letters regarding services or information requested by you, such as invoice objections, changes to  <br>electric service account information, and certifications. We may also use it to offer you additional services or  <br>to deliver marketing messages. | This information resides on our billing system from when you started your electric service. You may provide it  <br>again when you fill out a service request form. | This information is not stored by the Online Services. It is passed from the form to the service center. |
| Physical address | To send technical personnel to visit you in order to provide you services requested, such as streetlight repairs  <br>and tree trimming. | This information resides on our billing system from when you started your electric service. You may provide it  <br>again when you fill out a service request form. | This information is not stored by the Online Services. It is passed from the form to the service center. |
| Geolocation | If you grant the Online Services permission to access your location, it may be used to identify your location  <br>within the power outage map, among other uses. | Captured when you grant your device and the Online Services permission to identify your location. | This information is not stored by the Online Services. |
| Electric service account number | We request this information in order to provide you services requested and access to our Online Services. We request it during the online registration process in order to authenticate you as the rightful owner of the electric service accounts that the Online Services will present. | This information resides on our billing system from when you started your electric service. You provide it when you fill out a request form for service or when you create sign in credentials to access the Online Services. | This information is maintained in the billing system. It is not stored by the Online Services. |
| Payment information | To enable you to pay your electric account fees due through the Online Services. | You provide it when initiating a payment to us through the Online Services. | This information is not stored by the Online Services; it is simply passed through to our payment processor. |
| Social Media Login Information | We may include this feature to make it easier to sign in to our Online Services by allowing you to use your social media sign in credentials. | You identify the social media you wish to use to sign in and our Online Services connect to it to verify your identity and grant you access. | The social media sign in information is not stored by our Online Services; it is simply passed through to the corresponding social media service. The social media service may, in turn, send us some of your profile information, which we may store in our Online Services. |
| Social Security Number | To identify you as a customer. | This information resides on our billing system from when you started your electric service. We may request the last 4 numbers when you create sign in credentials in order to authenticate you. | This information is maintained in the billing system; it is not stored by the Online Services. |

### About our email marketing program

When we collect your email address as part of the registration process or through any other contact you have with us, we will enroll it in our email marketing program. However, if you prefer not to receive our emails, you may modify your email preferences or unsubscribe using the links provided on our emails. This will remove your email from our marketing list, but you will still receive emails related to your service.

### What non-personal information do we collect and how do we use it?

In addition to the personal information listed in the table above, we may collect non-personal information from the device you use. This non-personal information cannot be used to identify you and it may be automatically collected from your device using cookies or other tracking mechanisms. This information may include the IP (Internet Protocol) address, internet service provider, cellular service provider, type of device (whether it is a smartphone, tablet, PC or other device), device characteristics, operating system, browser, referring URLs, time and date stamps, language preferences, country and location information (if you have granted your device permission to share it) among others. You can control the level of access granted to cookies, but, if you refuse access to cookies, some aspects of our Online Services may fail to work optimally.

This non-personal information is used for troubleshooting, to maintain the security and healthy operation of our Online Services, for website and App analytics (analytics refers to our efforts to understand the traffic to our Online Services and how they are used), and to establish session IDs, which are unique numbers assigned to you during your visits to keep track of your activity and to remember your actions. We collect this information to make it easier and faster for you to use our Online Services. None of this automatically collected information can be used to identify you; it simply helps us improve our Online Services.

### With whom do we share your personal information and why?

We do not sell, share, rent or trade your personal or non-personal information to third parties. We only disclose personal information to the groups identified below for the purposes stated below.

| Shared with | Purpose |
| --- | --- |
| Affiliates | We may share your personal information with companies that are part of our corporate team or work jointly with us in performing our daily operations and developing our business. |
| Service providers | We may share your personal information with companies that are not our affiliates but have agreements with us to provide us services that we need to perform our daily operations and to provide services to our customers.<br><br>An example of this is our handling of your payment information, such as bank account numbers or credit card numbers. We collect this data through our Online Services and pass them through to the company that provides us payment processing services.<br><br>Another example is social media log-in. We share some personal information with the participating social media networks in order to enable social media log-in.<br><br>When we share your personal information with third parties, we require them to keep it safe. |
| Authorities | We may share your personal information with competent governmental authorities if required by a subpoena, court order, order from a regulatory agency or similar mandate that binds us. We will only provide the information that is specifically required and necessary for the investigation or proceeding. |

### How long do we keep your information on our systems?

We will keep your personal information on our systems for as long as it is necessary for the purposes stated above. We may keep your information longer if a longer retention period is required by law.

### How do we keep your information safe?

We have implemented appropriate technical and organizational security measures to protect any personal or non-personal information we handle. However, despite our safeguards and efforts to secure your information, no electronic transmission over the internet or information storage technology can be guaranteed to be 100% secure, so we cannot promise or guarantee that hackers, cybercriminals or other unauthorized parties will not be able to defeat our security and improperly collect, access, steal or alter your information. Although we will do our best to protect your personal information, transmission of personal information to and from our Online Services is at your own risk. You should only access our Online Services from secure environments and using devices under your control. Never access our Online Services from devices not belonging to you or from shared devices.

### Amendments to the Privacy Policy

If this policy is amended, you will be notified through the Online Services and/or via email. You will be presented with the amended policy, which will state the date when the changes will be effective. You will be able to review the amended policy before continuing your use of the Online Services.

### Questions?

If you have any questions regarding this policy, please contact us at email or phone.

_Last update: March 4, 2021_

Pay My Bill
-----------

Work With Us
------------

Frequently Asked Questions
--------------------------

Electric service rates are not established by LUMA. They are established by the Puerto Rico Energy Bureau, or PREB. To see the most recent Tariff Book approved by the PREB, and/or the most recent Table of Adjustment Factors, click on "Continue".

##### Contact Info

PO Box 364267 San Juan PR 00936-4267

For news media inquiries ONLY, please send any questions or requests to [\[email protected\]](https://lumapr.com/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection).

##### Quicklinks

##### Resources

##### Subscribe

### Newsletter Signup

* Name
    
* Email

Copyright © 2024 LUMA Energy

Designed by [Carimus](https://www.carimus.com/ "Carimus Website")
